<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../../../schema/fhir-single.xsd">


{{:toc}}


<p>The IHE Mobile and
Distributed Medication Administration supplement introduces a new generation of
interoperability mechanisms to be used in distributed and mobile medication
workflows, namely in the requesting and registering of administration of
medication, in mobile systems or otherwise distributed systems.</p>

<p>The use of this
profile supports the administration of medication with a standard way to:</p>

<p>(optionally)
transmit the instructions for administration</p>

<p>register and exchange
information about the administration of medication</p>

<p>The Mobile
Medication Administration profile is intended to be compatible with hospital
settings, but also community settings on a mobile environment, or where CDA
documents are not used. For CDA
documents, refer to the IHE CMA profile.</p>

<p>The content of this
profile is functionally compatible with the CMA profile: it is the goal of IHE
Pharmacy to provide one consistent interoperability framework, which can be
implemented using different technical mechanisms.</p>


<p>The MMA Profile
enables mobile and lightweight web applications to register the planned and
actual administration of medication.</p>

<p>The uses for MMA
are:</p>

<p>An application
for a home care nurse, that receives the requests and informs the nurse about
the medications that each patient is scheduled to take in a given period.</p>

<p>An application
(or the same as above) for a Nurse, where the nurse can register the planned
(as above) or unplanned administration of medication</p>

<p>An application
for patients to receive updated medication instructions on their mobile device
and / or register the use of medication, e.g. by scanning the barcodes.</p>


<p>Further ahead, the
IHE Pharmacy Technical Framework will be extended to the entire medication
circuit, and the MMA profile is not expected to change during that extension.
In other words, while the MMA profile may incorporate changes due to
maintenance or changes in the underlying standards, it is not expected to be
redesigned when the entire medication circuit is implemented.</p>


<p>This supplement is intended to be fully compliant with the
HL7 FHIR specification, providing only use-case driven constraints to aid with
interoperability, deterministic results, and compatibility with existing
Profiles.</p>


<p>Currently the HL7<sup>®</sup> FHIR<sup>®</sup> standard is
in “Standard for Test Use” (STU) and may experience a large amount of change
during this phase. Readers are advised that, while the profiled components in
this supplement may not accurately reflect the most recent version of the FHIR
standard, implementations of MMA will be tested as specified in this
supplement. Changes to the FHIR STU will be integrated into this supplement via
the formal IHE Change Proposal (CP) process.</p>


<p> . To include compatibility with existing IHE
actors, this profile extends or adds the following actors:</p>

<p><b>Medication Administration Performer</b> – checks for and receives instructions for
administration of medications to patients, performs the necessary checks before
administering. </p>

<p><b>Medication Administration Informer</b> – sends the reports of the administration actions
performed.</p>

<p><b> Medication Administration Request Placer</b> – provides the instance orders of medication
administrations to the medication Administration Performer.</p>

<p><b>Medication Administration Consumer</b> – receives the reports of administration of
medications.</p>


<p>The structure of
this profile allows different systems to concur in the administration of
medications for several patients – whether they are remote systems, mobile
applications for professionals, or patient apps.</p>


</div>

